CONTACT

saramh13@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/saraschuster/

https://github.com/SaraSchuster

505.507.0464

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Excel
- •
- Power BI
- Tableau
- SQL
- Python
- Git/GitHub

PROJECTS

FARMING FUTURES DATA ANALYST CAPSTONE

Farming Futures analyzed recent changes in demographics amongst farmers as we have seen an uptick in younger farmers entering the profession as well as a resurgence of small and even micro-sized farms. This capstone project sought to pinpoint which areas of the country were seeing this influx of new farms and farmers and to contrast this rising trend with the previous status quo of large, monoculture farming by a rapidly aging population.

SARA SCHUSTER

DATA ANALYST

ABOUT ME

Starting my career in education has inspired a lifelong love for learning. During several years of work in restaurant management, I specialized in the role of food cost analyst and discovered a passion for data. The urge to explore that further led me to Nashville Software School, and eventually into a whole new career. Now I'm ready to put all of my data skills to use for the right organization.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Nashville Software School | July 2021- present

Six-month intensive program in data analytics and business intelligence. Emphasis on analytical reasoning through hands-on training in every stage of the analytics workflow. Projects used real data presented by Nashville employers.

- Experience with SQL, Excel, Python, Tableau, & Power BI
- Experience in remote collaboration
- Git and GitHub for version control
- Learning included communicating findings through presentations, storytelling, reports, and dashboards
- Focus on teamwork, teambuilding, and leadership allows students to integrate with analytical teams in the future

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Production Manager

Aromagregory | 2018 - 2021

- Handled customer communication, data entry and organization of all incoming/outgoing orders, quality control, and shipping
- Analyzed sales trends to predict and implement production schedules and fulfillment
- Trained new employees on procedures and standards.

General Manager

Zaxby's | 2017 - 2018

- Oversaw entire franchise and assisted at district level
- Responsible for scheduling, interviewing, truck orders, inventory, food cost analysis, employee training, meeting all inspection standards, coaching assistant management team, and onboarding new management staff for other area locations
- Used internal software to analyze weekly inventory and food cost data as well as to project sales and make necessary ordering and staffing adjustments

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Assistant Manager

Panera Bread | 2017-2018

- Responsible for managing shifts, coaching employees, hiring and training new employees, and adhering to all food quality and food safety guidelines
- As food cost specialist, responsible for all truck orders (\$15K/wk), full weekly inventory, daily baker pan-ups, daily produce orders, and running food cost data analysis
- Used internal software to analyze weekly inventory and food cost data as well as to project sales and make necessary ordering and staffing adjustments

Manager

Khan's Bakery and Cafe | 2014

- Managed front of house operations and trained new employees.
- Created Excel spreadsheets to assist owner in tracking inventory, food cost, and incoming custom orders
- Ran the cafe's social media as well as working all cafe positions (both front and back of house)

Middle School Teacher

Metro Nashville Public Schools | 2008 - 2013

- Courses taught: Eighth grade language arts, reading, and math; Seventh grade language arts, reading, math, science, and geography
- Eighth grade department chair and team leader for three years. Member of School Leadership Team for two years. Member of Schoolwide Positive Behavior Support Team for three years (wrote the school's SWPBS presentation proposal which was accepted and presented at the 2012 state SWPBS conference). Co-chair of the Project Citizen Committee for two years
- As department chair and team leader, heavy emphasis on analyzing student data to create individualized instructional plans to meet student academic benchmarks

Middle School Teacher

Alachua County Public Schools | 2007 - 2008

- Courses taught: Seventh grade language arts and reading
- Participated in a peer coaching team comprised of four other English teachers. Participated in "One Book, One School" interdisciplinary thematic unit. Facilitated a student knitting club

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School || Data Analyst Certificate University of West Florida || BA Middle School Education